Benjamin Cato

With over a decade of experience in **front-end development**, I thrive on infusing projects with creativity and passion. I excel in collaborative environments and approach each project as a work of art, taking pride in my role as the artist.

402 Bridgepoint Ln.
Woodstock, GA 30189
(404) 374-1696
bcato3000@gmail.com
bcato3000.github.io/portfolio

EXPERIENCE

Whereoware, Atlanta — Senior front-end developer

May 2023 - October 2023 (6 months)

Expertise in creating modular components via React and Storybook (via TypeScript) · Optimizing user interfaces for Optimizely (CMS) · Involved with front-end code review of PRs · Expertise in responsive web development and pixel-perfect UI · Team lead for multiple front-end projects · Composition breakdown of components · AA SEO optimization · Mentor of junior front-end devs · Collaboration with back-end developers for optimal data structure and CMS integration

BrainJocks / Perficient, Alpharetta — Lead front-end developer

April 2013 - July 2020 / December 2021 - May 2023 (8 years total)

Created SPAs via React for large-scale CMS platforms (Sitecore / Optimizely) · Modular components and applications via React and Storybook (via TypeScript) · Responsive web development expertise · AA & AAA SEO optimization · Team lead for a variety of enterprise projects and component library · HTML5 / CSS3 / Sass / LESS and JS · Design liaison · UI instructor of SCORE (our customized front-end software) · Mentor of junior front-end devs · Engaged in projects from inception to final production phase

Fleetcor, Atlanta — Senior front-end developer

August 2020 - December 2021 (1.5 years)

Front-end development fintech \cdot Collaborated with UI / UX designers and bridged the gap between graphical representations and technical implementation via vanilla JS, D3 Js for graphical interface \cdot Front-end code review of PRs \cdot Creator of global component library for enterprise purposes \cdot Provided front-end expertise for HTML / CSS / JS \cdot Unit-tests via Jest

EDUCATION

The Creative Circus, Atlanta — Interactive Development

Graduate: 2012 - 2013

Chattahoochee Tech, Acworth — Computer Science

Graduate 2001 - 2003

 ${\bf Kennesaw\ State\ University,\ Kennesaw\ -\ Computer\ Science}$

SKILLS

HTML5

CSS₃

Sass

JavaScript

TypeScript

Storybook

RESTful APIs

SPAs (React/Vue)

Node

Web components

Responsive design/dev

Cross-browser

Accessibility standards

Git

UX

Adobe creative suite

Figma

Agile / Scrum

Client-facing contributor

PC Windows

Mac iOS